# MOHAMED ALMAHDY

### **Mobile Applications Developer**

- @ engmohamedalmahdy@gmail.com
- **+201096475710**
- Nasr City, Cairo
- LightFeather42

- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/eng-mohamed-almahdy
- https://github.com/eng-mohamedalmahdy

#### **PROFILE**

**Mobile Apps Engineer** with **4+ years** of hands-on experience in Kotlin, Java, and Swift. Successfully developed and delivered **10+ mobile apps** across Android, iOS, and Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) in more than **5 different sizes Companies**. Possess solid knowledge in digital marketing, enhancing my versatility.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Android Developer | Tawuniya

**11/2024 - Now** 

• Developing the Tawuniya Drive App to enhance user experience for Cars services.

#### Mobile Application Developer | The Kupe Consultancy

**i** 03/2024 - 11/2024

• Developed the lon Community App, a residential compound community app showcasing developer projects.

#### Mid-Level Android Developer | DTag

**i** 07/2022 - 03/2024

- Contributed to 3 mobile apps:
  - Whizzy (iOS).
  - Samoolah for User & Agent (Android).

Software Instructor **2022 - Now** 

Delivered mobile development courses on **Light Feather's YouTube Channel**, and provided Android programming training for the **Ministry of Communication**, Conducted Android Development Bootcamps at **Kayfa Applied Schools**.

### Junior Software Developer | Virtual Worker Now

**i** 01/2022 - 07/2022

• Contributed to 2 websites and 2 mobile apps including Pet Materices.

#### Junior Android Developer | ElMnassa Innovation

**i** 07/2021 - 01/2022

• Participated in the development of 2 mobile apps.

#### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

### **EDUCATION**

Kotlin Java Swift

B.S Computer Engineering | Al-Azhar University.

**2017 - 2021** 

• Graduation Project: Zakerly ( E-learning Mobile App ) Grade : Excellent

### **FRAMEWORKS**

Android Kotlin Multiplatform iOS

#### ANDROID TOOLS

Compose Coroutines Retrofit Koin

Rx Java & Kotlin | Image Loaders | Room

Realm Hilt MocKK

### **SKILLS**

- Strong grasp of OOP, data structures, and algorithms.
- Skilled in using architecture & design patterns & Principles.
- Solid understanding of HTTP Requests and RESTful APIs.
- Skilled in multithreading, & libraries like Coroutines & GCD.
- Experience in other programming paradigms such as **Fp** & **Rx**.
- Expertise in version control systems such as Git and GitHub.
- Proficient in Gradle buildSrc & Plugins and catalog versions.

### **IOS TOOLS**

Ulkit Storyboard Auto layout Swift UI

GCD RX Swift & Cocoa Core Data

\_\_\_\_

Clean Arch.

Clean Mobile Arch.

Algorithms Unplugged

Gradle for Android

Head First OOA/D

RECENT BOOKS READINGS

My book list: HERE

Alamofire Kingfisher

### **Android Projects**

### Samoolah 🔒 🛎

- Services Provider App With 2 Distributions 1 For the Client 1 For the Technician
- Used Technologies: MVVM with Modularization Compose Rest APIs with Retrofit Navigation Component Kotlin Coroutines with Flows

### Islami 180 🔊 🛎

- Islamic application contains: Quran + Quran Tafseer Prayer Azan Qibla Finder Azkar Hijri Calendar Tasbeeh
- Used Technologies: MVVM Room database (for Quarn data storage) Retrofit (for prayer azan API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Work Manager Notifications Manager Alarm Manager Senesor Manager And more

### Zakerly 😱 🚈

- Zakerly is an app used to connect students with teachers to learn online as an E-learning service And helps them attending online sessions individuals or groups
- Used Technologies: MVVM Firebase Kit (real time database & cloud messaging) Realm database (for data storage)
   Retrofit (for FCM API requests) Android navigation component Json to Gson serialization Jitsi meet sdk

### **iOS** Projects

### Whizzy 🕳

- **Description**: Whizzy is a revolutionary mobile application designed to simplify the process of renting electric cars for short rides. With its user-friendly interface and advanced features, Whizzy aims to provide a modern and convenient solution for urban commuters looking for eco-friendly transportation options.
- **Used Technologies**: MVVM architecture with Swift UI, Alamofire for networking, Kingfisher for image loading, Combine GCD for asynchronous programming.

#### 

- Pet Matrices is a lifestyle application for your pets where you can record and track your pets activities and given calories, you also can record and track their health condition and get some nice advice from an expert
- Used Technologies: SwiftUI, REST API, MVVM archticture pattern, Swift GCD

### Memorise 🕠 🗯

Memorising game created with swift and Swift UI.
 A project for Stanford CS193p course at: https://cs193p.sites.stanford.edu/

#### **■ Kotlin Multiplatform Projects**

### Masarify **■**

- Innovative expenses tracker App
- leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms. Demonstrated proficiency in KMP, delivering a feature-rich application with multi-account support, dynamic categories, and multi-currency.
- Used Technologies: MVVM -CMP- SQLDelight KTor Voyager Router KotlinX Serialization KAMEL

#### Ion K

- Residential compound community app that also shows the developer other compounds and projects.
- Online-based, leveraging Kotlin Multiplatform (KMP) for seamless development across multiple platforms.
- Used Technologies: MVI CMP KTor Voyager KotlinX Serialization KAMEL

## More Projects at my GitHub O